$100 while working, $200 while sleeping.
일할때는 100달러, 잠잘때는 200달러
I've finally applied for channel monetization, surpassing 1,000 subscribers and 4,000 watch hours.
제가 드디어 구독자 1,000명 하고 4,000시간 넘어서 채널 수익창출 신청했습니다
Since I already had an AdSense account, I used that existing one.
저는 애드센스 계정이 먼저 있었기 때문에 기존 계정 가지고 했고요
I believe it's all thanks to you, my subscribers, and I'll share everything I can.
우리 구독자님들 덕분이라고 생각하고 제가 풀 수 있는 건 다 풀겠습니다
I said I'd share what I can, right?
제가 풀 수 있는 건이라고 했잖아요
There are things I really can't.
진짜 못 푸는 게 있어요
If I reveal those, my channel will be ruined.
그거 풀면 채널이 망해요
But if you follow what I'm teaching now, you'll eventually figure it out on your own.
그래서 그거는 어차피 제가 지금 알려드리는 걸 하다 보면 스스로 깨달으실 겁니다
The moment you understand that, you’ll be making so much money, it'll make even Steve Jobs look like an amateur.
그걸 깨닫는 순간 이사양 잡스는 저리 가라 할 정도로
So, don't worry too much about it, and I'll share everything I can.
엄청난 수익을 벌어들이실 거기 때문에 너무 아쉬워하지 말고 제가 가능하면 다 풉니다
The AdSense ecosystem keeps changing.
애드센스 생태계가 계속 변하죠
The logic of Daum, Google, and Naver also keeps changing.
다음이나 구글이나 네이버 로직도 계속 변하는데
I'll try to keep up with those changes as quickly as possible and share what I learn.
그 변하는 거에 맞춰서 가능하면 빨리 제가 해보고 알려드릴 거니까요
So keep getting great information through me, your Isayang Jobs.
계속 제 이사양 잡스를 통해서 좋은 정보 얻어가시고
And whenever you feel shaky as a digital nomad, stay strong and keep going.
디지털 로마드 하면서 한 번씩 휘청휘청 할 때마다 마음 다잡고 가시면 좋겠습니다
Also, I'm constantly expanding my pipelines.
제가 그리고 지금 파이프라인을 계속 늘리고 있거든요
I don't know how far I’ll go.
어떻게까지 하시는지 모르겠어요
For example, you invest in stocks or real estate, right?
예를 들면 주식이나 부동산 이런 거 하시잖아요
In the digital nomad world, we do AdSense, AdPost, Coupang Partners, and so on.
이쪽 디지털 로마드 쪽에서는 애드센스, 애드포스트, 쿠팡 파트너스 이런 식으로 하는데
But you can't rely on just those because the income fluctuates a lot.
그것만 해서는 안 됩니다. 왜냐하면 수익이 들쭉날쭉해요
AdSense is relatively more stable in terms of income.
그나마 애드센스가 수익이 안정적인 편이에요
AdSense is what gives you a steady income,
꾸준한 돈을 만들어주는 거는 애드센스인데
but the others aren't stable yet.
나머지 것들은 아직 안정적이 아니기 때문에
So, you need to keep expanding your pipelines, build a base with the ones that survive,
파이프라인을 쭉 늘려놓고 그중에 살아남는 것들을 가지고 또 기반을 다지고
and then keep adding more pipelines.
또 다른 파이프라인을 늘려갈 수 있어야 됩니다
To create a new pipeline, you need to have stable lines already in place.
파이프라인을 새로 하나 팔려면 분명히 안정적인 라인들이 이미 설정이 돼 있어야 합니다
If you do that, you’ll keep adding new things, and eventually, you'll be able to earn money even if you do almost nothing.
그렇게 하시다 보면 새로운 것들을 늘려나가고 나중에는 정말 거의 아무것도 안해도
Or, you can just post what you need to. Right now, you write blog posts even when you don't want to.
혹은 꼭 필요한 것만 올려도 지금은 블로그 글 쓰기 싫은데 막 쓰시잖아요
Because it's trending, right?
이슈가 되니까 쓰시지 않습니까?
You write informational posts after studying, even when you don’t know what they're about. But once things stabilize,
무슨 내용인지도 모르는데 정보성 글 쓰라고 하니까 공부해서 쓰시는데 안정화가 되시면 그때부터는
you can write about what you know well, what you want to share, and your income will still be stable.
정말 내가 잘 알고 알려주고 싶고 내가 쓰고 싶은 글을 써도 수익이 계속 유지될 수 있습니다
That's great, isn't it? Let's keep going together until then.
너무 좋은 일이죠. 그때까지 함께 계속 하시면 좋겠습니다
Okay, today, as I mentioned in the title, and now that I have ads, I'll try to place them well.
자 오늘은 제가 제목에서 말씀드린 것처럼 아 그리고 이제 광고 달리니까 제가 광고 한번 잘 달아볼게요
For us AdSense users, especially bloggers,
우리 애드센스 사용자들은 블로거들은 특히
the click-through rate varies greatly depending on where you place ads.
광고 배치를 어디다 하는지에 따라서 클릭률이 차이가 많이 난다는 거 아시잖아요
In my previous video, I showed you how to use mobile full-screen ads.
제가 이전 영상에서 모바일 전면 광고도 활용하는 법 알려드렸습니다
Like that, for us digital nomads doing AdSense,
그것처럼 우리 애드센스를 하는 디지털 로마드들은
writing articles and creating videos are important, but strategic ad placement is also important.
글을 쓰고 영상을 만드는 것도 중요하지만 이 전략적으로 광고 배치도 중요합니다
I'll try to place ads well on my YouTube channel too, according to the content I make.
유튜브도 제가 하는 채널 내용에 맞게 광고 배치를 한번 잘 해볼 테니깐요
Please support me, I'm counting on you.
잘 도와주십시오 부탁드립니다
I think my channel will last a long time if you do.
그러면 채널이 계속 오래 오래 갈 거라고 생각합니다
I'll always be grateful, and let's start today.
항상 감사한 마음을 가지면서 오늘 시작하겠습니다
Today, what I want to show you is...
오늘은 제가 뭘 보여드리고 싶냐면요
I want to talk about top ads.
상단 광고를 말씀드리고 싶어요
You place top ads, right?
상단 광고 넣으시죠
Whether you’ve been doing YouTube or AdSense for a long time or not,
어... 유튜브 어... 애드센스를 오래 하셨든 그렇지 않든 간에
the place with the highest click-through rate and the highest revenue is the top ad.
어찌 됐든 가장 클릭률이 높고 수익이 높은 곳은 상단 광고입니다
So, we can't not put ads at the top.
그래서 상단에 있는 광고를 안 넣을 수가 없어요
Since we can’t avoid it, we cannot overlook this point.
안 넣을 수가 없기 때문에 우리가 그 점을 간과할 수는 없는데요
How you place the top ads can affect your session duration, bounce rate,
상단 광고를 어떻게 넣느냐에 따라서 체류 시간이나 이탈율
and even your cost per click (CPC).
그리고 더 나아가서 단가까지 조정이 될 수 있습니다
So, you need to place them smartly.
그러니까 좀 똑똑하게 넣어야 돼요
You’ve just been placing them and maintaining them because they made money, right?
그동안 그냥 넣어 왔는데 수익이 났다고 해서 유지해 오셨었잖아요
So you just think, "Whatever."
그래서 에라 모르겠다
You don't want to deal with the headache of figuring it out, so you stick with it because it's making money.
머리 아프고 공부하기 싫으니까 돈은 일단 들어오니까 이대로 계속 가자 라고 하시면
That might not be helpful in the long run.
장기적으로는 별로 도움이 되지 않을 수 있습니다
Today, I'll tell you about a few types of top ad placements.
오늘 제가 상단 광고 넣는 몇 가지 유형을 말씀드리겠습니다
First, there are people who place them like this.
먼저 이렇게 넣으시는 분들이 있어요
The first top ad placement I'll show you is like this:
첫 번째로 보여드릴 상단 광고 배치는 이런 겁니다
When it's above the title when you enter the page.
들어왔을 때 제목보다 위에 있는 경우입니다
In this case, the ad might be seen first, but the problem is, what happens if the ad doesn't load quickly?
이런 경우에 광고를 먼저 보게 될 수는 있겠지만 문제는 광고가 빨리 뜨지 않으면 어떻게 될까요?
It appears as a blank space. Then people will scroll down right away.
공백으로 나옵니다 그러면 사람들이 바로 올리겠죠
These days, phone speeds and internet speeds are faster,
실제 요즘에는 핸드폰 속도도 빨라졌고 인터넷 속도도 빨라졌기 때문에
so if it doesn't load within a fraction of a second, people notice and scroll down immediately.
0. 몇 초 안에 뜨지 않으면 사람들은 금방 인식하고 손가락으로 올라갑니다
As someone who plays an instrument, you know the hands are faster than the eyes. So if it doesn't load, you scroll.
악기를 연주해 보시는 분은 알겠지만 눈보다 손이 빨라요 그래서 안 뜨면 바로 올리게 돼 있습니다
So, even if you want to show it immediately, if it doesn't load, they scroll down.
그러니까 아무리 바로 보여주고 싶게 했더라도 안 뜨면 올라가는 겁니다
Also, if there's an ad as soon as you enter, what comes to mind? Those clickbait pages written by clickbait journalists.
또 하나 들어오자마자 광고가 있으면 뭐가 생각납니까? 기레기들이 쓰는 기레기 페이지가 생각나잖아요
If they hate that, they might leave the page right away.
그러면 이걸 엄청 싫어하시는 분들 뒤로 나가 버릴 수가 있어요
Another one is an ad right below the title.
또 한 가지 제목 바로 밑에 붙는 광고입니다
I showed you how to place it in the skin editing in my previous video.
이건 제가 지난번에 스킨 편집에서 어떻게 넣었는지 알려드린 적이 있는데요
Once you place it there, just like the previous one,
거기서 한 번 넣어 놓으면 이것도 마찬가지고 이 위에 것도 마찬가지고
if you put the ad code in the skin editor, it will automatically appear.
스킨 편집에서 한 번만 광고 코드를 넣어 놓으면 이렇게 자동으로 뜨잖아요
It's very convenient.
굉장히 편합니다
And it loads faster than the Kakao account linked version, which is why I recommended it before.
그리고 카카오 계정 연동한 것보다 광고 나타나는 속도가 빠르기 때문에 제가 저번에 추천드린 거예요
But, when you do it this way, it's the same here too.
그런데 이런 방식으로 했을 때 여기도 마찬가지입니다
If the ad doesn't load right away here either, it will appear blank.
여기도 광고가 바로 뜨지 않는 경우에는 공백으로 표시되고
And people might think it doesn't look good.
사람들은 디자인적으로 별로 좋지 않다고 생각하거나
Or they might think there's nothing there and scroll up before even seeing the ad.
아무 것도 없다고 생각해서 광고를 보기도 전에 위로 올릴 수 있는 거예요
So, placing ads above like this should be a conscious decision, except for specific situations.
그러니까 이 위에다가 광고를 넣는 거는 특정한 경우를 빼고는 선택을 하셔야 됩니다
I'll explain later when placing these ads can be beneficial.
이 광고를 많이 넣는 것이 언제 좋은지는 제가 뒤에다가 설명을 해 놨는데
But for now, I'm talking about creating a pension-like blog.
일단은 제가 지금 말씀드리는 거는 궁극적으로 연금형 블로그 있잖아요
Not a post that you use for two or three days and throw away.
글을 한 번 써서 2-3일 써먹고 버리는 포스팅이 아니라
I'm talking about blog posts that will keep generating income,
이 써놓은 게시글이 두고두고 나에게 수익을 갖다 주고
and you want the session duration to keep going up.
체류 시간도 계속 오르길 바라는 그런 블로그인 경우를 제가 말씀드리는 겁니다
In that case, putting ads above the title, or the ad appearing before the main content,
그런 경우에는 이 제목 위에 넣는 거 또 제목과 본문 사이에 광고가 먼저 뜨는 것이
clearly contributes to a higher bounce rate,
사람들로 하여금 이탈률을 높이거나
and reduces readability, so I don't recommend it.
가독성을 떨어뜨리는데 분명히 일조를 하기 때문에 추천드리지 않는 겁니다
So, what do I recommend? It's this:
그럼 제가 추천드리는 방식은 뭐냐면 바로 이겁니다
As you can see here, you understand, right?
여기 보시는 것처럼 이해가 가시죠
When someone first comes to your page, what they want most should be at the top.
처음 들어왔을 때 사용자가 와서 가장 원하는 부분이 원래 위에 있어야 됩니다
It shouldn't start with an ad and ruin the design.
처음부터 광고가 나오고 디자인이 무너지고 이러면 안 되고
The title comes first. The title appears first, followed by the main content.
제목이 먼저 나왔죠. 제목이 나오고. 본문이 먼저 나왔습니다
The main content appears for about four or five lines. And then the ad appears.
본문이 네 줄 다섯 줄 정도 나왔어요. 그리고 나서 광고가 나오는 겁니다
It's still a link ad, so I used a link ad as an example.
아직까지 링크 광고가 되니까 제가 링크 광고로 예를 들었어요
If you read the text above, you’ll be willing to wait until the ad loads even if it's a little delayed.
그러면 위에 글을 보다 보면 광고가 좀 늦게 뜨더라도 광고가 뜰 때까지 기다릴 수 있겠죠
If you place the ad in this area, you will definitely see the ad.
이 부분에 광고를 위치시키면 무조건 광고를 볼 수 있게 되어 있는 겁니다
So, it's a great method.
그러니까 굉장히 좋은 방법이에요
And I told you before to put the description at the top.
그리고 제가 예전에 디스크립션을 맨 위에다가 넣으라고 그랬잖아요
So, the most important information, the answer, should be in the first paragraph.
그래서 첫 문단에 가장 중요한 내용 정답이 될만한 내용이 들어가 있어야
So that people can read the content in the introduction while waiting for the ad to load, for 1 second or 0.5 seconds.
광고가 뜨기까지. 1초 혹은 0.5초가 지나기까지
They can read the content in the introduction while waiting for the ad to load.
가장 서론에 있는 내용을 보면서 광고가 뜨기까지 기다릴 수 있습니다
The ad appears here. But it might not be an ad they like.
여기서 광고가 나왔어요. 광고를 봤는데 마음에 드는 광고가 아닐 수 있죠
Or they might want to see the content below.
혹은 밑에 있는 내용을 더 보고 싶을 수가 있어요
What will they do then? They will scroll down.
그러면 어떻게 할까요? 올립니다
When they scroll down, the H2 tag appears with a title and the main content continues.
올렸을 때 이제 H2 태그가 나오면서 제목과 본문 내용이 또 이어집니다
But as you can see, while reading this main content, they see another ad.
근데 보시는 것처럼 이 본문 내용을 보는데 또 광고가 보이죠
The ad should be placed so it can be seen anywhere on the page.
이런 식으로 광고가 어디서든지 볼 수 있게 구성이 되어 있어야 되는 거예요
It shouldn't be like this, for example:
예를 들면 이렇게 돼 있으면 안 됩니다
If the content covers the ad,
광고를 가리고 글을 볼 수 있게끔 해 놓으면
people can easily scroll past the ad without seeing it.
사람들이 얼마든지 광고를 보지 않고 스쳐 지나갈 수 있는 광고 배치가 되는 겁니다
So for example, they see the first paragraph and then see the first ad.
그러니까 여기서 예를 들어서 첫 번째 문단을 보면서 이 첫 번째 광고를 보죠
But they don't want to see the ad, so they cover it.
근데 광고 보기 싫잖아요. 가렸습니다
Does covering it mean they won't see the ad? They will still see it.
가렸다고 해서 광고를 안 보나요? 그래도 광고를 보게 되는 겁니다
If you design it like this, the ad will continue to be visible. If a targeted or contextual ad appears,
이런 식으로 구성을 하면 광고를 계속 시각화하고 그중에 맞춤 광고나 문맥 광고가 나왔을 때
they will likely click on it if they like it.
마음에 드는 광고가 나오면 클릭하게 될 수밖에 없는 거죠
We tend to place ads carelessly, but especially these kinds of ads are not good.
우리가 무심결에 그냥 막 넣는 광고, 특히 이런 광고는 안 좋습니다
There's a paragraph, then an ad, and then another ad below it.
문단이 있고 광고가 있어요 근데 이 밑에 또 광고인 겁니다
If you do this, the ad will be right under the first ad.
그러면 이렇게 되면 이 첫 번째 광고 바로 밑에 광고가 붙죠
You can scroll past all of it without seeing it.
이거 싹 밀어서 아예 안 볼 수 있는 거예요
So when you place ads, don't assume people will only look at the ads.
그러니까 광고를 넣으실 때는 광고만 볼 거라는 착각은 하시면 안 되고
They will be looking at the main content, and the ads will naturally be within their peripheral vision.
가장 중요한 본문 내용을 보면서 광고는 자연스럽게 우리 눈의 주변 시야 있잖아요
You need to keep that in mind. They'll see it like this. They'll see the second one like this.
주변 시야로 볼 거라는 계산을 하시면서 보셔야 됩니다. 두 번째도 이렇게 보시고
For example, as I mentioned before, nobody looks at it like this.
예를 들어서 아까 말씀드렸지만 이렇게 보는 사람은 없죠
Nobody likes ads so much that they look at them like this.
광고를 너무 좋아해 가지고 광고를 위해도 이렇게 보는 사람 없습니다
If it's placed like this, they will naturally look at it this way.
이렇게 만약에 배치가 됐다면 당연히 이렇게 보게 될 겁니다
Like I said before, just put two ads at the top, somehow.
제가 예전에 말씀드린 것처럼 상단에 광고 두 개 어떻게든 넣으시면 돼요
Place them there, and when there is good content in the middle, don't put too many ads.
배치하시고 중간에 제대로 된 내용이 있을 때는 광고를 많이 안 넣고
And place ads at the very end. So they can make a decision then.
가장 마지막에 넣어주시면 마지막에 결정을 하거나
Or they can scroll back up and click the ad. I told you about that before.
다시 올라가서 누를 수 있다는 얘기 드린 적이 있습니다
Do you agree? Placing the ads like this.
어떻게 동의하시나요? 이런 식으로 광고를 넣는 것을
If you want to set it up as the third method that I suggested,
만약에 제가 지금 제안 드린 것처럼 세 번째 방법으로 세팅을 하길 원하신다면
how can we achieve this when we write a post?
우리가 글을 작성할 때는 어떻게 하면 이런 세팅이 가능할까요?
I'll show you.
제가 한번 보여 드리겠습니다
This is the new post page of my Isayang Jobs website.
여기는 제 이사양잡스 홈페이지 새 글쓰기 들어왔는데요
First, write the title: "Ads will soon be on the Isayang Jobs YouTube channel."
먼저 제목을 쓰시고 이사양잡스 채널에 곧 유튜브 광고가 달립니다
Thank you for subscribing.
구독 감사합니다
Okay, I'm just writing that for fun.
네 이렇게 괜히 한번 써보고요
I told you about the description before, right?
제가 예전에 디스크립션 말씀드렸잖아요
Write the description part.
그 디스크립션 부분을 써 주세요
If you just do what Google tells you to, it will naturally work out.
이게 그러니까 구글이 그냥 시키는 대로만 하면 원래 자연스럽게 되게 돼 있어요
For example, let's say I wrote a description like this. 160 characters.
여기다가 예를 들어서 이렇게 디스크립션을 썼어요. 160자죠
"The Isayang Jobs channel will soon have ads thanks to the great love of subscribers."
이사양잡스 채널이 구독자분들의 큰 사랑에 힘입어 곧 광고가 송출됩니다
I’m new to YouTube, so the ad placements might be annoying,
유튜브는 초보라서 광고 배치가 짜증날 수도 있으시겠지만
but if you keep supporting me as you have been, I will provide you with more tips as an AdSense and digital nomad.
지금까지처럼 응원해 주신다면 더 오래오래 애드센스와 디지털 노마드로서
I will give you tips on how to have an easygoing life.
무사태평 살아갈 수 있는 꿀팁을 전달해 드리게 될 것입니다
I've subtly revealed my true feelings, and now you've written the description.
이렇게 저의 속내를 은근슬쩍 드러내면서 일단 이렇게 쓰셨잖아요
We agreed to write the description like this, right?
디스크립션 이렇게 쓰기로 했죠. 저랑 같이
Then you can put an ad.
그 다음에 광고를 넣으시면 돼요
Leave a space and create the ad placement.
한 칸 띄우시고 이 광고 배치 위치를 만드시면 됩니다
Create it like this and then, here is the top ad placement method.
이렇게 만드시고 그 다음에 여기다가 상단 광고 배치 방법
An H2 tag will be placed like this.
이런 식으로 H2 태그가 들어갈 겁니다
The tag will be inserted, and more content will be below it.
태그 들어가고 여기에 또 밑에 내용이 들어가겠죠
Content will be written like this.
이런 식으로 내용이 들어갈 겁니다
So, one space here, two spaces here. This is my style. I like this.
그러면 한 칸 여기 두 칸 이건 제 방식이에요. 저는 이걸 좋아해요
I don't like to put them too close together.
은근슬쩍 안 갖다 붙입니다
I like to clearly show the ads.
저는 확실하게 광고를 띄워주는 걸 좋아하기 때문에
And then, go to the HTML and place the AdSense ad in this part.
그리고 html 가셔서 이 부분에 애드센스 광고를 넣어 주시면 되겠습니다
Then, when you return, it will be like this. This is the ad part. Some people place ads using the form,
그러면 돌아오면 이렇게 되겠죠. 여기 광고 부분이고 서식을 통해서 넣으시는 분도 있는데
but in my experience, this is just my feeling,
제 경험상 제 느낌입니다
it seems like the new editor breaks the AdSense ads a little more when you place them using the form.
신 에디터가 서식으로 넣으면 조금 더 애드센스 광고가 깨지는 경험을 한 거 같아요
It may not be true.
아닐 수도 있어요
So, it's your choice, but I still place ads directly using the HTML code.
그러니까 본인 선택이신데 저는 아직까지는 html 코드에서 직접 넣고 있습니다
So, put in two lines of description, leave one space, and place the AdSense ad.
이렇게 디스크립션 두 줄 넣으시고 한 칸 띄우시고 애드센스 광고를 넣으시고
Leave two spaces and then start writing your content.
두 칸 띄우신 다음에 본격적으로 글을 써 나가시면
Just like we saw on the blog, the first four lines.
아까 블로그에서 봤던 것처럼 처음에 네 줄
On a typical phone, whether it's an iPhone or Galaxy, the main content will appear for about four lines.
일반적인 핸드폰에서 아이폰이나 갤럭시에서 네 줄 정도는 본문이 나오고
The title will be above it, and the ad will take up 50% of the rest of the screen.
위에 제목이 달리고요. 나머지 화면에 50%가 광고가 보입니다
You only need to place one ad here.
여기 광고를 하나만 넣으셔야겠죠
If you put two, what happens is you look at the ad, right?
두 개 넣으면 어떻게 되시냐면 광고를 보지 않습니까
You see it and scroll down. And then there's another ad.
보고 나서 올리죠. 올렸는데 또 광고인 거예요
Then you will start to quickly scroll down.
그러면 이제 팍팍 올립니다
And then it doesn't go the way we intended.
그러면서 이제 우리의 의도대로 넘어가지 않게 되는 거예요
So, just one ad here.
그래서 여기는 광고 한 개만
Whether you put a display ad or a link ad, place it like this.
디스플레이를 넣으시던 링크 광고를 넣으시던 이렇게 해서 배치하시면 되겠습니다
Then you can use the top ads like this.
그러면 이제 상단 광고를 이렇게 사용하실 수 있겠어요
The method I didn't recommend before is the one above, this one.
제가 아까 추천드리지 않는 방식은 여기 위에 이 방식이죠
This method can cause the ad to load slowly.
이 방식은 광고가 늦게 뜰 수도 있고
And even if the ad loads, people didn't come to see the ad.
광고가 뜨더라도 원래 광고 보려고 들어온 게 아니니까
They scroll down, and they can push away the ad and just view the content.
올리고 여기서부터 광고는 밀어내고 볼 수 있는 방식입니다
Even putting an ad above the title might be good in some cases.
심지어 이 제목 위에 제목 위에 광고가 달리는 것도 좋을 수는 있어요
If you’re only focusing on trending keywords, it's a bit different.
내가 만약 실검만 하시면 조금 이해가 다릅니다
For trending keywords, you need to put a lot of ads.
실검은 무조건 광고를 엄청 많이 넣어야 돼요
Because you'll only be using the post for three or four days.
왜냐하면 그거 한 3일이나 4일 쓰고 버릴 글이거든요
It's a post that's going to bring in 50,000 visitors in 3 days, attracting 10,000 or 15,000 visitors a day, and then you will throw it away.
하루에 10,000명씩 혹은 15,000명씩 3일 동안 5만 명 확 땡긴 다음에 버릴, 어차피 난리일 포스팅이에요
So, session duration is not important.
그러니까 체류시간 이런 거 필요 없습니다
You need to make sure people see the ads as much as possible.
그런 거는 어떻게든 광고를 사람들 눈에 많이 띄워야 되기 때문에
So, you can put them above, here, there, and even put two ads at a time.
이 위에도 넣고 여기도 넣고 여기도 넣고 광고도 한 번에 두 개씩 넣고
Doing it this way is effective.
이런 식으로 하는 거는 효과적입니다
The top ad placement that I'm talking about now is for posts that you want to keep ranking on Google,
제가 지금 말씀드리는 이 상단 광고 배치는 구글에서 꾸준히 노출하고 싶은
that you want to use like a pension, and if you write really good, valuable content,
연금처럼 사용하고 싶은 것이라면 그리고 내가 글을 정말 잘 썼어요 가치있는 글을 써서
that users will find helpful,
사용자가 이거를 보고 도움을 받았다고 생각할 만한 그런 글을 쓰실 때는
placing the ads before the main content isn't very helpful, that’s what I’m trying to say.
광고 배치가 본문보다 먼저 나오는게 크게 도움이 되지 않는다는 점을 말씀드리는 겁니다
I used to put them at the very top.
저도 옛날에는 맨 위에 무조건 넣었어요
I would always put them at the top and place as many ads as possible, here, there, in the middle, everywhere.
무조건 넣고 광고 어떻게든 많이 여기도 넣고 여기도 넣고 중간에 계속 넣고 곳곳에 다 넣었습니다
As a result, the speed was slow, and there was no improvement. It was all just hard work.
결과는 속도도 느려지고 발전이 없었죠. 계속 힘만 들었습니다
I was doing a lot of digital labor.
디지털 노가다를 엄청 한 겁니다
But after changing my ad placements,
그런데 제가 광고 배치를 바꾸고 나서부터는
the posts that were generating revenue had a higher click-through rate, higher revenue,
수익을 내주는 글이 클릭률도 올라가고 수익도 올라가고
and were more stable. And as a content provider,
더 안정적으로 그리고 글을 제공하는 입장에서도
I used to feel a sense of shame for writing clickbait and things like that.
그전에는 낚시성 글을 쓰고 이런 거에 대해서 본인 스스로도 좀 자괴감이 들고
I didn't feel good about it.
별로 기분이 좋지 않았습니다
I always said to my wife,
그때 제가 맨날 속으로 저희 아내한테도
I would say “This clickbait is really hard on my mental health.”
아 기레기 비슷한 이런 거는 진짜 멘탈이 너무 힘들다 이렇게 얘기를 한 적이 있었어요
But now, while I expect the revenue to naturally come, I'm writing the content to be most helpful for users.
근데 이제는 수익은 당연히 따라올 걸 기대하면서 사용자에게 가장 도움이 되는 방식으로
And I started thinking about the ad placement while I was trying to do that.
글을 쓰기 위해 노력을 하면서부터 이런 광고 배치도 고민을 하게 된 겁니다
I thought about how to do it in a way that is helpful to the users and doesn’t violate Google AdSense policies.
사용자 입장에서 구글 애드센스 정책을 위반하지 않는 입장에서 어떻게 할까 고민하면서 썼더니
As a result, it actually became helpful to the users, and as the poster, I didn't feel ashamed.
실제로 사용자에게 도움 되고 글을 쓰는 게시자인 저도 자괴감에 휩싸이지 않고
Right, and the revenue went up.
그쵸 그리고 수익도 올라가게 되어있습니다
Of course, I'm not saying this is the correct answer.
이게 물론 정답이라고 말씀드리는 건 아니에요
There may be other ways that work well when it comes to top ads, but
상단 광고에 대해서 실제로 여러 가지를 해보시면 효과가 있겠지만
If there are people who want to get help from my experience,
제가 미리 해본 제 경험을 통해서 도움을 받고 싶으신 분이 계시다면
then I recommend doing this.
제가 이 점을 추천드리는 겁니다
So, if you want to create a valuable main blog,
그래서 앞으로 메인 블로그를 좀 가치 있고
a blog that will keep increasing in value like a pension,
연금처럼 꾸준히 상승하는 블로그로 꾸미고 싶으시다면
when you place top ads, let go of your greed and place them from the user's perspective.
상단 광고를 넣으실 때 욕심을 버리시고 사용자 입장에서 넣으시기를 권해드리겠습니다
Okay, that's it for today.
네, 오늘은 여기까지 하고요
There's one more thing I want to mention about top ads.
상단 광고 관련해서 한 개 더 언급해드릴 게 있어요
I'll talk about that again soon.
그거는 제가 빠른 시일 내에 또 말씀드리겠습니다
Until then, try this and see how it goes, I'd be interested in your results.
그 전까지 적용해보시고 효과가 어떤지 기대해보시면 좋겠습니다
Ads are most important for us.
광고가 우리에게는 가장 중요하죠
The Isayang Jobs channel is also very important.
이사양잡스 채널도 가장 중요합니다
Please take care of us.
잘 부탁드리겠습니다
Thank you.
감사합니다
This was Isayang Jobs.
이사양잡스였습니다